Deep in the concrete canyons
of Harlem, New York
stands a basketball court
where the legends of
the game are born.
Rucker Park.
Between the lines of
this battleground,
a great many tales of
warriors have come and gone.
But there was one player
whose talent soared
far above the rest.
His name, Uncle Drew.
- So good.
- Incredible.
Like, scary good.
- Dominating.
- Dangerous.
- Best of the best.
- Bananas.
I mean, you knew he just
brought things to the game
that the game had
never seen before.
Changed the face of basketball.
Drew been dangerous since birth.
My pops played him one-on-one
in the seventh grade.
He broke my pop's ankle.
True story. Gym teacher
gave him a "D."
You know, he'll
show you one trick,
then beat you with
another trick.
Shakin' people's sneakers off.
They fallin' out the trees.
He was a bad man.
He went to one end of the court,
shot the lights out,
went to the other
end of the court,
shot it back on again.
Man, he was good
enough to be the logo.
Wait, I thought you
were the NBA logo.
It's actually Uncle Drew. They
just shaved his afro off.
One time, he took
on "The Destroyer"
and beat him only
with his left hand.
And then, hold on. Wait for it.
With his right hand, he was
eating a ham sandwich.
Was there anyone out there
better than Uncle Drew?
With word of Sandwichgate
and Black Ankle Sunday both
spreading like wildfire,
Uncle Drew and his
childhood friends
shot to the top of the first
Rucker Classic in '68.
But it was not long before
it all came crashing down.
It had to be something
concerning him and a female.
We knew that.
Uncle Drew and the ladies? Yeah.
Man, the rumor was
Drew slept with
one of his teammate's girl
the night before the finals.
And when it came time
to play in the finals,
they were all a complete
and total no-show.
And after that he
just disappeared.
Despite the mysterious
disappearance
of its greatest player,
the fabled park is
still the epicenter
of the streetball universe.
The question is, will this
year's Rucker Classic
see the birth of a new
playground legend?
Give me that.
- Yo, what's up?
- What was that?
Hey, what's the problem, man?
Mario was open.
Maybe Mario was open,
maybe he wasn't.
But you know what
- the problem with that is?
- Huh?
Mario. Hey, I don't
know what you doin'...
- Close your ears!
- Mmm-hmm.
Mario is terrible. Okay?
Look at him.
I just told a grown man
to cover his ears,
- and that's what he just did.
- Coach, what are you saying?
Grab the ball, Casper.
- You are my Beyonce. Okay?
- Beyonce?
Not Dantay, not White
Dantay, not Regular Jeff,
not Little Melvin, not Little
Melvin's stunt double.
Okay, they're just
Destiny's Children.
You are the star.
You are my Queen B.
- All right.
- Let's make Lemonade, man.
Score the rock.
All right, now look
here, everybody.
I'mma say this once. Nobody
else shoot the ball.
Just Casper. Let's go.
Dax Winslow. Sal
Masekela, SlamMagazine.
- SlamMagazine, huh?
- Yes, sir.
You mind if I get a
couple of sound bites?
Do I mind? No, you shoulda
been talking to me.
Um...
How does a guy who
works at Foot Locker
get a beast like Casper Jones
to play for him in Rucker Park?
Game recognize game.
He's the best player.
I'm the best coach.
We gonna take it all.
I'm telling you, this
dude is amazing, man.
Put me and Casper on the cover.
- You know who that is, right?
- Know who who is?
Who Mookie Bass is.
A.k.a. that
Macklemore-lookin' dude
that's makin' eyes at
your meal ticket, man.
The hell is he doing here?
Hey, what's up, Dix?
First of all, you
know my name is Dax.
A "bag of Dax" don't
make no sense.
What is that? What's that smell?
Is that a grudge?
Are you still holdin' a grudge
'cause I blocked your shot?
I have no recollection
or even know what you
even talkin' about.
Okay, let me refresh
your memory, then.
You're about to hit
a three-pointer.
Outta nowhere, a little
white boy comes up...
Bam! Blocked that shot, I
think, with my armpit.
Well, but I do remember,
there was that Spalding...
You didn't even jump that high.
So like nipple...
It was high enough
that I could see
your face like this.
You were like...
Okay, stop! That's not...
I didn't do that.
What are you doin'? Stop.
Casper, take it from the top.
Do something, y'all.
Defense, Dantays, figure it out.
Casper Jones, huh?
Could you just literally
give me some space, man?
Yo, you seen this tat
though, right here?
That's the one where I blocked
your shot and won the game.
And then these are the only
ones that really matter.
Bam! Seven of nine
Rucker Championships.
But don't you worry, Dix.
I got plenty of length on
my Dax for the next one.
I don't care. I don't wanna
hear about your man junk.
Is there a point to all this?
Yeah, I guess my point is,
when you have a
history of winning
as many titles as I do,
cats like Casper Jones,
they have a way of
gravitating towards you.
So I'll see you when
I see you, Dix.
Hey, Casper. Hey, man, let
me talk to you real quick.
- What's up, coach?
- We good, right?
You know what I mean?
Me and you.
- Yeah, we all right.
- Do you need anything?
You know what'd be dope?
The new Space Jams.
They are amazing. They
pretty expensive, like $225.
- Straight fire, though.
- They fire.
But you know what?
I just thought about it.
I sold the last
pair this morning.
The good news is, in
another week and a half,
we get new stock, and I
got a pair just for you.
- Okay. I like that.
- Yeah. You like that?
Yeah, yeah, we all right.
I got you, brother. So
it's me and you, we good?
- Yeah, we rollin'.
- You with me.
- I'm with you, dog.
- Forever.
- Dax and Casper.
- Yeah, you my bro.
- All right, man. I love you.
- Love you, too, man.
- We good, right?
Yeah, no doubt. All right.
Cool.
Don't worry, Dax.
Don't worry, Dax. We'll
find you a family.
- Yes.
- All right!
We'll find you a family.
Yes!
Yes! Yes!
Oh! What a move by Jordan!
Jordan with the moves!
Man, what an inspiration!
Just listen to the crowd!
They love him!
They love him! They love him!
Yes!
Yo, can we run with you?
Yes, yes.
No!
You need to be on the bench!
- He's worthless!
- You suck, Dax!
- You need new glasses!
- He's the worst!
You suck!
Dax, that was unbearable!
Dream sequence...
Boy, you better than cable.
Look, you wouldn't
even understand, okay?
It's terrible.
Dreamin' about that
little white boy
slappin' that ball
out your hand?
- Now, how do I look?
- You look expensive.
Man, you know I can't
afford Gucci on my salary.
Which is why when you and
Casper win the Rucker
and the $100,000 check
that come with it,
we'll be just fine.
Baby, I thought that 100K,
we was gonna use
to start a family.
I want a Tesla.
I would look so cute in a Tesla.
And I'd have the little
screen on the side
and then I could be like,
"Boop, boop, boop, boop!"
And all my homegirls
gonna be like,
"Look at Jess killin'
'em in a Tesla."
Well, I mean, this sounds like
a beautiful, beautiful
dream and everything,
but I didn't hear
my name one time.
You didn't say, "Oh, Dax
was in the Tesla with me."
Baby, you gonna be there, too.
It's gonna be me and you,
and we just gonna be
one big happy family.
I love that.
Well, don't let the
ghost of white boy past
scare you out of
gettin' this money.
You win this game, and
you win this money,
and bring it back home.
- I'm motivated, baby!
- Whoo!
Bam! That's right. These shoes
right here are classic.
I wore these shoes last
night, little man,
and I had a quadruple-double.
- Look.
- That's right.
I didn't want to say this,
but he isn't even that good.
Why would you say
that about your baby?
Are you a stepmother
or something?
- You the real mother?
- Yeah.
You shouldn't...
Oh, you know something?
Matter of fact,
Larry, help her out.
- Hey, baby.
- Oh! Hey, girl!
I thought we were
goin' to lunch today.
You right. We supposed
to have lunch.
Yeah, I'm very hungry.
I been shoppin' all day.
Look it.
I know. Look, do me a favor, babe.
Just give me a second.
Just go look at some
shoes or something.
Do they got them new RiRis?
RiRis, BeeBees, whoever you
need, it's over there.
Do they got 'em? Because,
you know, I do not wanna
be shoppin' unless I can
get them new RiRis.
'Cause she a savage, too.
You a savage and you fine.
- I'm fine?
- Yeah.
Well, boy, you better shut up.
Over there, look at those RiRis,
you know what I mean?
I see you, boo.
- She ready. Yeah!
- She ready.
Oh. Do you see the
RiRis over here?
Yo, my main man, Casper.
What up, brother?
What up, Dax? How
you doin', man?
The myth, the legend
in the makin'.
Hold that thought.
Man, I'm confused. I thought
these were out of stock.
Bruh, the truck
came this morning
and dropped off a
new stock of shoes.
I was gonna call you.
So you gonna hook us up, then?
Oh, so you want me to get
shoes for everybody.
Everybody.
This dude, and this guy...
If you can't do it, I got
plenty of people that...
I got you. I'mma
take care of you,
and your whole squad.
Yeah, okay. Yeah,
that's a lot better.
Taxes included.
After I put in my
employee discount,
which will probably
get me fired...
The total is $833.50.
Everybody, it's on Dax.
It's on... It's on Dax.
Shoes for all y'all.
Oh, hey, Casper.
Oh, hey, baby, how you doin'?
Good, how you doin'?
Oh, baby, that's our
meal ticket right there.
Oh, my goodness.
Let me show you what
I found on Zillow.
I found a really
cute brownstone.
Two bedroom, hardwood floors...
Transaction denied.
Damn it!
- Excuse me, what's goin' on?
- Damn what?
Marty, don't worry about it.
Aw, hell no.
If the money for these shoes
that just magically
flew out of here
don't come up in 60 seconds,
you and Miss Belly
Out goin' to jail.
What the hell you talkin' about?
First off, I didn't
do nothin' wrong,
so I ain't goin' to jail.
But thank you for noticin'
that my belly's out.
Come here, come here, come here.
What?
That kid that just left here...
Mmm-hmm?
He's gonna change
our lives forever.
50 percent.
I mean, at the most, I
could do 49 percent.
You got 30 seconds, brother!
All right, 50 percent.
Cool!
It's nice doin'
business with you, boo.
50 percent. I'm
gettin' 50 percent.
Marty, did you hear that?
50 percent.
Yo, yo, yo, yo!
Look at this, man. Fresh
off the presses, y'all.
Harlem Money, you see that?
Come on, y'all, look!
Go grab your jersey, come on.
I didn't know you got
money for second place.
Hey, man, what the
hell you doin' here?
Why don't you enlighten
this fool, C-Dawg?
- C-Dawg?
- I'm C-Dawg now.
New team, new nickname.
- Wait, what?
That's what I said to him.
I was like,
"C-Dawg, don't you
wanna be coached
by a dude who looks like an M&M?
What about a dude who looks
straight up like a basketball?
Like a Syracuse Orange man."
I've spent my life savings
just to get in this tournament.
I gotta give my girlfriend
half the winnings
or she's gonna leave me.
I took three buses and a train
just to pick up those jerseys.
Those Jordans, man! You
know how much that cost me?
Yo, by the way, thank
you for the kicks.
They are mad expensive.
There was no way I
was gonna buy 'em.
All right, boys, let's roll.
Come back here!
Dantay! Other Dantay!
- Casper, take off those shoes.
- I'mma hold these.
You hear me, Casper?
Take off those shoes!
And comin' in at number one
onSportsCenter's "Not
Top Ten" list...
With the Rucker 50 right
around the corner,
we have a meltdown
from New York City.
I'm told the man you see here
is a coach named Dax Winslow.
And, Dax, the good news is
you're onSportsCenter.
The bad news is...
Dax!
What's up, girl?
What'd I do wrong now?
I have so many questions.
You're rolling around
on the ground,
trying to take
somebody's sneakers
off their sweaty feet?
Is this your team? Are
these even your players?
Come on, man!
Dax, this is Rucker, man.
Have some respect.
Damn you, Scott Van Pelt!
Give me the shoe, Casper!
Right now!
Flopping around on the
ground like fish.
Everything gonna be
all right, okay?
I'mma figure something out.
I can't do this anymore.
Excuse me?
Do you think that I'm
countin' on you?
'Cause I'm not. No, I
was counting on Casper.
And you lost him. You
can't even do that right.
Go in there, pack your
stuff up, and leave.
You can't just kick
me out our house.
This is my apartment.
Do you even remember the
last time you paid rent?
Okay, every Taco Tuesday,
who buy the $2 tacos?
Don't nobody care
about no damn tacos!
Okay, I paid the water bill
- that one time.
- Get out my house!
Jess, I ain't got nowhere to go.
You know?
I didn't have no family.
And then I met you.
And you took me in. And
you changed my life.
Baby, we in this together.
You're my everything.
Please, just let me stay
here and figure things out.
Hey! Don't leave
with my bag, fool.
Where I'm supposed
to put my stuff?
Leave with what you came with!
Fine, I'll give you back
your stupid, fake bag.
It's not stupid, you stupid.
My bag is smarter than you!
Give my shoes back!
This is Rucker, man.
You're supposed to
have some respect.
You're rolling around
on the ground...
trying to take
somebody's sneakers
off their sweaty feet?
I know y'all think this is
all fun and games and stuff.
But I used everything I
got on this tournament.
Did you get a receipt? Huh?
No, man, the money's
non-refundable.
That's cold.
This a perfect opportunity
for Dax to meet Uncle Drew!
Don't start that in here with
the old and the Uncle Drews.
You're trying to throw a
toothpick in a lumberyard.
The man is the greatest
blacktop player
I ever seen in my life.
He's real. I've seen
that boy put up
40 points against
The Destroyers.
Using just his left
hand and his chin.
His other hand, he
had a ham sandwich
with extra cheese on it.
And mayo. He likes mayonnaise.
Okay, come on, man,
that's just like
talking about Bigfoot.
Bigfoot. You can't compare
Bigfoot to Uncle Drew.
Son of a bitch used
to date my sister.
He used to date my
sister and my mother.
He actually hit
- my eighth grade teacher.
- Ooh!
Ain't none of my business what
that man does in his bedtime.
I know he had a foot fetish.
All right. The '60s was a wild time.
Okay? So what?
Remember them Buicks?
Everybody had them damn Buicks.
You'd ride around, had
them big old back seat.
You can't move your hips.
But you can still
move your lips.
Hey, I ain't gonna
go no further.
All you need is some Viagra,
and some dress socks.
Ain't have no damn
Viagra back then!
You had to get two ice-cream
sticks and a rubber band
to make the stuff
stand up like that.
I don't have time for this, man.
I gotta go.
Hey, whoa, whoa. Hold on, Dax,
hold on. Now, look.
You need to go holler at Uncle Drew.
Okay?
He's a Zen master of basketball.
But you gotta believe.
Hey, look. Maybe he was good.
But you think this old man can still ball?
Come on, bruh.
I'm good, man. I gotta
find some players, man.
You'll be sorry, Dax. Don't
do that to yourself.
Get with Drew! Get with Drew!
Welcome to the jungle, baby.
Get out of here. Go corner,
corner, corner! Corner!
Over here, over
here, hold on, son!
See, that right there,
that's the problem
with your generation.
Million dollar move and
a five cent finish.
You haven't made a shot yet.
- Come back!
- Come on!
- I was open.
- I had to shoot it, man,
I've taken out trash that
don't stink as bad as that.
Dr. Naismith would be
rolling in his grave
if he knew what these
bums is up to out here.
You talk a lot of smack
for a geriatric.
It's a shame you can't
back any of it up.
And who's to say I can't?
All right, then, what's the bet?
If you win...
I'll leave the park and
I'll never come back.
- Good.
- Real good.
But if I win, you and your crew
start playing the game the
way it's meant to be played.
Oh, how's that? On
a peach basket?
It's like a perfectly
orchestrated symphony.
What?
Not any instrument is more
important than another.
And what's in it for you?
Love, youngblood. Only love.
What is this dude talking about?
What the hell does
that even mean?
What are you talking about?
Hold my nuts.
Hold your nuts?
Hey, J! Look at
this dude out here.
Everybody off the court.
Get off the court, man. Get
your big behind off the court.
Hey, man. Give him the business.
Ball up.
Hey, young fella, you
better watch that.
Aren't you gonna get
in your stance?
I am in my stance.
Don't worry, grandpa.
Gonna have you home in
plenty of time for NCIS.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Hey. For the show I know though,
even a bum ain't as broke
as your jump shot.
- Give it to him, J.
- Prove it.
You wanna see it rain?
Let it rain.
Raindrops. 2-0.
Next basket wins it.
It's getting to be about
that time, ain't it?
Yeah, give it to him.
This game is over.
It's time for you to
change your PIN number.
'Cause you just got robbed.
- Come on back.
- J, come on, son!
You want me to tell you
your first mistake
or your second?
What's the matter, you
forgot the score?
One. You got too cocky.
There's a fine line between
confidence and
arrogance, youngblood.
Come on back. Come on back.
And then, two, you're
giving up your lead hip.
You might as well
unlock the door
and have your wife show
me where the china is.
I wouldn't do that
either if I was you.
Come on, J! No, no!
He cookin' your boy.
Man, you need to go back there
and play with them kids, man.
I get buckets.
Shut up, old man.
Go on, youngblood.
Check ball.
This game is all mental.
All mental.
Hand down, man down.
- Anybody got a GPS?
- Come on, J!
You know, gonna need a whole
new zip code on that one.
Game point, youngblood.
Whatever.
You ready?
Yo, I'll give you that.
Nah. Nah, don't give him that.
You still don't believe, do you?
Get your hand up!
No, don't give it to him.
Don't...
Don't do him like
that, Uncle Drew!
Youngblood.
Good game.
Who is that dude?
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Oh...
Oh, my God, man.
That was a pretty amazing
show you put on back there.
It was one of the
greatest things
I've ever seen, honestly.
How're you doing?
M-my name is Dax.
I'm not interested.
I haven't even told you
what I'm trying to do.
Okay, okay.
You can't believe someone
that looks like me
can play like Jordan,
Magic, or Bird.
You want to take
advantage of that.
See if you can cash in somehow.
I know your MO.
What? No, no. You got
me all wrong, man.
Look, I just want to talk to you
about the Rucker, you know?
The Rucker?
You don't know nothing about
no real Rucker, youngblood.
Exactly. You right. I
don't know anything
about the Rucker. A
lot of us don't.
But someone like you
could help us, man.
We could combine the old school
with the new school, right?
Like a old school,
new school remix.
Where you can educate
all the youngbloods
who are lost in
their way, right?
And show 'em what they're
really doing wrong.
You can do that.
Is a lot of lost youngbloods
out there, huh?
It is so many lost youngbloods
out here, it is ridiculous.
If I could help them, I would,
but I don't know,
because I'm lost, too.
Okay? And that's
why we need you.
Look, look, look.
Perfect example.
This is, this is who you are.
You a lonely lighthouse
in a sea of fog.
I actually kind of like that.
- I like that.
- That's good, ain't it?
Yeah, yeah, that's
good, that's good.
That's what I'm telling you.
You are coming to
the rescue, man.
You get a chance to teach this
in front of a bigger audience.
At the Rucker. The Rucker.
Rucker.
The Rucker would be nice.
I'll tell you what. I'll
do it on one condition.
Yes!
Anything you want. I don't
care what it is. I got you.
It's gotta be my team.
My boys.
Okay. Anything but that.
No. Because it's my team.
Yeah, I guess we done here.
Dax whatever...
Okay, okay, okay.
I'm in, okay? My team.
Your roster.
It's my team, my roster.
Look, where you goin'?
It's a long drive
to Chocolate City.
Wait, Chocolate City?
What's in D.C.?
Preacher. He's the best power
forward I ever played with.
I mean, you don't know
no local power forward?
Somebody that stay
in the neighborhood?
Here she is. Yeah.
You know, so if
Billy Dee Willams
and Diana Ross had a love child,
it would've definitely
been inside this van.
Go on and look way back there.
Go ahead. Take a look. Take
a look way back there.
That right there is
the boom boom room.
Boom boom room come
with one rule.
No shoes in the boom boom room.
So, I could wear shoes
throughout the rest of
the part of this van,
but if I go a couple feet back,
I gotta take my shoes off?
Why do I gotta take my
shoes off back there?
And I can leave my shoes
on, like right here?
It's the same space.
Well, it's the living room,
and then it goes to
the boom boom room.
See, that don't even make
sense because it's a van.
Everything is right
next to each other.
Let's go over the
rest of the rules.
No, but I'm saying that don't...
Hey, don't be slamming my door.
Oh, I'm sorry about that.
Hey, man, you just
did the same...
Now, let's go over the rules.
One. I'm the pilot.
Means I steer the ship.
Two. I'm the weatherman.
I control the heat.
Did you just say heat?
I don't know if you know.
It's the middle of summer,
so maybe you should...
Three. Don't be
questioning one and two.
Can't help it if I'm running
a little cold these days.
Four, I'm the DJ, which
means I control the music.
Whoo!
What's that? Is that a Game Boy?
- Electronic book?
- Mmm-hmm.
You gonna see.
Oh, yeah! You hear that?
You hear that?
- That's a eight track?
- You hear that?
Come on, come on take a ride
That ain't no jive
Can't we just go
to Chocolate City?
Don't even have to drive
Can you at least
turn down the heat?
Slippity-slide
My glasses are sweating.
Just sail on
That's what I do Just
sail on, that's what I do
How you dancing like
that in a jogging suit?
Are you not hot?
I'm really creeped out.
Gotta get the boys.
I gotta turn up the heat a
little bit though. Yeah.
Please don't turn the heat up!
We've been listening
to this song
since this morning.
It is nighttime!
Oh, yeah.
- Mmm.
- Ooh!
What you know about this, Drew?
I thought this was gonna
be a boring road trip.
You got the classics
playing, man!
What you know about the
classics, youngblood?
I know a lot, man.
How did you get Biggie
Smalls on a eight track?
That's crazy, man!
Junior M.A.F.I.A.!
Junior what?
You know what I said.
You know who they are.
To all my ladies in the place
With style and grace,
allow me to...
Okay. Okay.
New rule, youngblood.
None of this
rappity-hippity-hop nonsense.
You understand?
What you mean
rappity-hippity-hop?
That's not what it's called.
It's called hip-hop.
My car, my version.
Talking about styling.
What is that?
First of all, I can tell
you don't have style.
'Cause you always got
on jogging suits.
Talkin' from the hustler
with the fake chains.
These are real. I got
these for my birthday,
- so go about your business.
- Yeah, right. Those cost...
- Three checks!
- Those cost
- fifty cent a piece.
- Three checks!
My teeth cost more than that.
This is real music. Now
listen to the words.
At least as far as I can see
Oh, yeah.
Can see, I want to keep you here
Laying next to me
That's what I tell my girls
in the boom boom room.
Love between the sheets
Ooh, this is my favorite part.
Go ahead.
- My baby, ooh - Okay.
I'm sorry.
- Baby, baby, my love
- I'm sorry.
Stop sing... You're ruining it!
First off. Watch your tone.
Look, here we go. Just listen to it.
Give it a try.
Come on.
You see how quick I did that?
I just pushed play.
I ain't have to take
out an Atari cartridge
- and stuff it in the radio.
- Okay, okay. Pause, pause.
How do you pause it?
Okay, youngblood.
There ain't gonna be
none of that nonsense
here in my car right now.
You gonna call this nonsense.
This is one of the
greatest MCs of all time.
Yeah, what about the
Isley Brothers?
I don't know too much
of their history,
- but I'll Google it later.
- What is Google?
Hey, man, is this a church?
Heck else it's gonna be?
Did we road trip all
the way out here
to pick up an actual preacher?
You got a problem with that?
No, I don't have a
problem with it, man.
But I thought it was,
like, a nickname,
like "Hot Sauce" or "Crazy
Legs" or "The Glove."
Amen. Amen, Amen.
We're gathered here
today to bear witness
to the anointing... Ha!
The christening... Ha!
The blessing... Ha!
Of this young rookie soul.
And it is with the
purity of heart we pray
that he will one day grow
to drive the paint...
Why is he holding him like that?
Crash the boards of
moral righteousness.
No, no, please, no.
My man Kevin Durant started
a new beginning in Golden State.
You preach, Preacher.
He's gonna dunk a baby.
One for the money
Two for the show
Three to get ready
Whoa, whoa, wait, wait!
Hey! Man! What are you
doing with that baby, man?
You can't baptize a baby.
You cannot do that.
- You cannot...
- Hey, Dax.
- Dax, sit down.
- Drew, let me go. I got this!
That is a baby, okay?
You christen a baby, right?
You hold the baby, right?
Maybe splash a little
water on his face.
He gonna cry a little
bit but no big deal.
You don't dunk a baby
in a baptismal pool.
What type of parents
are y'all to let this
really large man
pick your baby up?
He did it like this.
He put your baby
behind his back.
You gonna let this man
Steph Curry your baby?
That's insane!
Uh, maybe the midget's right.
Yeah. Can we have our baby back?
Is there something I can
help you with, son?
Dax. Give it a break.
- No!
- Sit down!
I'm not sitting down, Drew!
I'm taking a stand.
- All right.
- Thank you.
All right, I warned you.
Where you from, son?
I'll tell you where I'm from.
I'm from New York City, okay?
Look here, Tiny Tim.
Took me almost an hour
to fill up that pool.
Somebody's getting
baptized, you understand?
Dunk this potbelly Teletubby!
You can't talk to me like that.
Y'all wanna baptize him?
- Yeah!
- What?
Bring him on up.
Dunk him like a fat donut.
- Dunk him, Preacher.
- What are you doing, man?
- That my boy, Drew.
- Mmm-hmm.
Drew, you gotta make him
take one for the team.
For the team!
No, no, no.
Gonna have to take one for the team.
Oh, yeah.
What you mean, "Take
one for the team"?
Drew,
just like back in the day
when we used to hoop,
you could still throw
the alley-oop.
Thank you for throwing
me this lost soul.
One last run at the Rucker?
Hmm.
50th anniversary.
You know this is more
than a 50th anniversary.
This here, divine intervention.
I wouldn't call it all that.
I'm gonna have to run
it by Betty Lou though.
Run what by Betty Lou?
Drew's putting the squad
- back together.
- Yep.
You forget what happened
to you, Preacher,
when you get between them lines?
No, no, no. I just
ain't laced 'em up
in a while, that's all.
And there is a reason for that.
Quick question.
What exactly is "a while"?
I mean, is that like
a few weeks or...
30.
- 35 years. Still nice, though.
- 35 years.
Wait, 35 years? Come on,
man, that's ridiculous.
Our little hobbit is right.
It's ridiculous.
It's God's work that matters now.
Not basketball.
Just because it's God's work,
don't mean it's not still work.
His work is never done.
Now, I've had about
enough of this.
Book of Psalms, chapter
62, verse one and two.
Fool, please. Book of Psalms,
chapter 23, verse four.
Ephesians five,
chapter 22, boom!
Book of Betty Lou, chapter
one, verse "I said so."
You heard the woman. I can't go.
One, it wasn't no
black hobbits, right?
And, two, that is one
mean churchwoman.
She ain't supposed to be
calling me ugly like that.
Okay, and I'm handsome.
I'm the short version
of Idris Elba.
The ladies say it
all the time, man.
And is he even coming?
- He's coming.
- How do you know?
Basketball is in his blood.
Same as it is in mine.
Both of y'all old as hell, okay?
And I at least saw
you play first.
I need to see him
shoot at least.
Youngblood, you can't
teach seven feet.
What you mean you can't
teach seven feet?
- What are you talking...
- Hallelujah!
Man can only take
so much nagging
before he done had enough.
I told ya.
He could have got in
here without yelling
"Hallelujah" in my ear, right?
Preacher, you're supposed
to take your shoes off
in the boom boom room.
You're gonna tell me the
rules of the boom boom room?
I'm just trying to make sure
we're clear, that's all.
Oh, Lord.
Spoke too soon.
Why are we slowing down?
Light just turned red.
So? Run it, fool! You know
how worked up she can get.
Oh, no, I ain't trying
to get no ticket now.
Preacher!
I know you in that van!
She got a baseball bat
in a church dress?
I am Betty to the Lou.
They don't even know
who they messing with.
Don't you know any players
that don't require a road trip?
And what's the deal
with Betty Lou anyway?
It's just one weekend.
Is it me? Or is
it nippy in here?
It ain't just you.
What is wrong with you two?
I am melting over here.
Good. Looks like you could
stand to lose a few.
Is it just me, or is
little man's head
abnormally large for his body?
Hey, youngblood, how much does
your neck hate your head?
- Big head, little neck.
- Funny jokes.
He was a baby bobblehead doll.
Wobble, wobble, wobble.
Actually, my head is the
most normalest size
you could think of.
I've measured my head.
Well, you sure got some
little ass ears then.
Mama deserve a purple heart,
passin' a melon that big.
Anybody else use a disco nap?
See, now that is a
good idea, Preacher.
My eyelids been heavy all day.
Seriously?
These two are unbelievable.
You good?
All set.
Still a little nippy
in here though.
That's strike two, youngblood.
The next one, you gonna
be riding on the roof.
Not with that big
ass head, he can't.
Too much wind resistance.
Hey, Preacher, can I
ask you a question?
Can I say no?
What happened to y'all
back in the day, man?
Why did all y'all disappear?
Gotta ask him that.
So, Drew, what happened in 1968?
Nothing a few Ws can't fix.
You really think
basketball could fix
what happened with
you and Big Fella?
Why not?
Play the game the right
way, it fixes everything.
You say so.
Come on, man. Okay, could
you get a jug or something?
You really love
basketball, don't you?
What's there not to love?
Basketball's the most
reliable thing in the world.
Don't complain, don't
ask any questions.
You bounce it, comes
right back up.
What about you, youngblood?
You ever play?
Nah, not really.
Why not?
'Cause I don't.
What's that supposed to mean?
It means what I said, okay?
I just coach, all right?
- I don't believe you.
- I don't play, okay?
All right. Well, you're up.
Wait a minute, I thought
you was the pilot.
I need you to
co-pilot for a spell.
Address is on the dash.
Don't mess up my car.
Aw, snap!
Prostate ain't what
it used to be.
How many times you gonna
use the bathroom?
Jesus, man. Need like a
built-in toilet in his shorts.
Now, please enjoy the
latest in sports.
Let's go to Rucker Park
where our man, Scoop Jackson
is interviewing seven-time
winner, Mookie Bass.
Oh, you gotta be kidding me.
Scoop Jackson at the
Rucker 50, Harlem, USA.
Here with my man, Mookie Bass.
- Damn, Mookie.
- So, why do you keep
doing this, man? You have
a history of just winnin'
and winnin' and winnin' this.
When is it ever gonna stop?
Hey, that's a great question, Scoop.
It's like,
"What keeps you motivated?"
You know what I mean?
And for me, it's a rivalry.
Its power is derived
from rivalry, you know?
-Seriously? -What is
your source of power?
When Thomas Jefferson sent
car keys up in the sky,
and then it got
hit by lightning,
and that started the first car.
This don't even make sense.
Now, I'm no scientist, so
don't quote me on this.
Although I do have a degree
from Trump University.
But every power has a
source for that power.
So, what's your source, then?
He know who he is and we'll
just leave it at that.
Bam!
Shoutout to Pepsi.
Shoutout to Oberto.
Shoutout to Aleve,
the number one painkiller
in the game right now.
And there it is.
I'mma just get out of here.
Rucker 50, Tournament
of Champions,
all going down in three days,
here in Harlem. Three days.
I'm coming.
Three days, you going down, Dix.
Damn, there's a lot of trees.
Hey, man, you're not
kidnapping me, are you?
I'm serious. I saw
the movieGet Out.
The only reason I'm
still in this van
'cause you're a old black man.
But if you was white...
Drew, could you tell
your girlfriends
to get across the street?
Something I can help
you gentlemen with?
Looking for an old friend.
First name, Wilbur,
last name, Wallace.
You mean, Lights?
Check the D&B across the street.
He likes to get his
shots up before lunch.
Yeah, that is Lights.
See, that's what I
am talking about.
Somebody actually practicing.
Oh!
Yeah, that's it.
- Swish!
- Oh, that was all net.
- Good job.
- Boom, baby!
Buckets.
Girl, you should've seen
me back in the day.
Whoo-hoo!
Well, how'd I do?
It's the highest score
of the year, Lights.
That means you buying
drinks, right?
That's exactly what that means.
Means she's too nice to tell
a old turkey like
yourself the truth.
Wait a minute.
Drew!
- Lights.
- Drew!
What's going on, man?
I'm right here, I'm right here.
What's going on?
Okay, now.
How's the release?
Oh, come on, Drew. Just
get me to my spot.
Once a shooter,
always a shooter.
What do you mean, "Once a
shooter, always a shooter"?
This dude shot
nothin' but bricks.
Damn, Preach. I didn't
even notice you over here.
Who else did you
roll in here with?
He's right there.
Hey, man. Brother! Okay,
this is my personal space.
Sorry.
Now, I got a question, because
I've been seeing a lot
since I've been here.
Are you blind?
Legally or actually?
That don't even make any...
You know something?
I'mma... I'mma chill out.
Drew, can I talk to
you for five seconds?
Yeah, yeah. You chill out.
Trying to find my boy, Boots.
Oh, I'm Maya. Boots
is my grandfather.
Oh. Boots. Great
to meet you, Maya.
Where's the little
shrimp, anyway?
Not good, Drew. Not good.
Grandpa.
Grandpa, you have some
friends here to see you.
Right over there.
You want to say hi?
Heads up, little man.
Yeah. O.G.
- He still got it.
- Yeah.
There he is.
How you doing, Boots? Ah, man.
Band back together, huh?
Nah, I love you, too, bro.
It's good to see you now.
Hey, little lady,
everything okay?
It's just been years since
he smiled like that,
and even longer since
he tried to stand.
Excuse me. You said this man
hasn't walked in years?
Yeah. A lot of years.
Look here, Drew. I ain't
trying to break up
your bromance,
brother, but, come on.
It's no time for
that, youngblood.
Gotta get Boots here
packed and ready to go.
I'm sorry. Packed for what
and ready to go where?
You didn't think
that we was gonna
leave here without him, did you?
Okay, look, Drew, right?
- Uncle Drew.
Can I just talk to you for a
second over here, please?
Okay, here's the deal.
I am all for him
getting a break from this place
'cause, quite frankly,
I could use one, too.
But his doctors have him on a
full psychiatric lockdown.
So, that means no trips.
Just means we gotta
break him out.
No, that's illegal.
Break out? Do you
even hear yourself?
You are insane!
You're the coach, ain't you?
Figure it out.
Now, look, everybody.
Just like on the court,
- it's all about timing.
- Okay.
And I got the plan. Here we go.
Lights, I need you to
go in, and I need you
to distract these
nurses here and here.
Once that happens, Preacher,
I need you to go in and penetrate.
Right?
All the way to the psych
ward and set a back pick...
- What is a back pick?
- On the security guard.
But make sure you do
that, a good pick.
A good forward does a good pick,
and that's what I
need you to do.
Once that happens, Drew,
you're my all-star, brother.
I need you to sneak in there,
right, and get Boots
undiscreetly...
- Undiscreetly?
- Take him to
the freight elevator all
the way to the roof.
You know he's in a wheelchair?
Once you get to the roof,
guess who's there? Me.
Your boy. I'mma have a rope...
- Rope?
- What do we do with that rope?
We tie the rope securely
on the wheelchair.
We will lower him down
- nice and slow...
- Whoa, lower?
Until...
Who is it?
You know, I don't
mind you being here,
but I had to draw all this up
for you just to roll
down here on your own?
Look, just get in the van.
Pure magic.
Think I don't know what
you're up to, little man?
You think you're
slick, don't you?
This ain't nothing but
a full-court press.
I'll just take your rook, boom!
Hold up. Wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
Run that back, man.
Run that back. Double
or nothing this time.
Double or nothing this time.
So, you sure you
really wanna do this?
You know, this van is
full of old people,
and it's already smelling
like pee and Poligrip.
That is true. But I wanna see
my grandpa happy, you know?
Why do they call
your grandpa Boots?
Well, it's an interesting story.
He wore the same worn
out pair of kicks
every time he stepped
foot on the court.
He refused to play
in anything else.
He would tell people that
they were his work boots.
You know, I think
it's really sweet
what you're doing for them.
We all need something
to look forward to,
even if it is just a pipe dream.
What do you mean, pipe dream?
Uncle Drew is the real deal.
Yeah, but you don't actually
think they could win, do you?
I mean, that's what
makes it so sweet,
is that you're doing it anyway.
You're basically just setting
$5,000 on fire to
see them happy.
If you ask me,
that's pretty noble.
Exactly who I am, you know?
Dax the Noble.
We got a blind guy, a guy
who can't even walk,
and a preacher who still
keep a perm in his head.
What's wrong with this next guy?
You wanna tell him or should we?
Tell me what?
Don't even worry about it.
Oh. Sure you don't want
us to go with you?
Some songs are best sung solo.
Dibs on the van if he
actually kills you.
Hold stance.
Remember, my young grasshoppers,
without the proper focus,
you will never truly
master your mind and body.
Yes, Sifu.
It is also important
to remember,
without a good defense,
your offense means nothing.
Yes, Sifu.
Now, go in peace.
Get out of here.
Look like a scene out
of Game of Death.
All these years, and you
still ain't figured out
that the best defense
is good offense, huh?
It's good to see you, Big Fella.
- Oh, my God, they're fighting.
- What happened?
- Okay.
- Go get him.
Drew got knocked out, man.
I got to be the getaway driver.
I brought my driving gloves.
That dude is a giant.
Best drop step in the business.
Sup, Big Fella?
That sucker punch is the first
free throw you ever made.
Putting the team back together.
I can't do that unless
you're on board.
How about we play
one-on-one for it?
Can't always play your
way out your problems.
It's worked out
pretty good so far.
- Has it though?
- Okay, okay. Hey, hey.
Time out!
Large karate man, excuse me.
You look like Wolverine's
grandfather.
That's none of my business,
that's your look.
Okay, I get it. Uncle
Drew is annoying.
He's been getting on my
nerves for the last few days.
So, you don't have to do
this for him, that's cool.
But what about the
rest of these cats?
One last time around
the block, Big Fella.
What about Lights?
In the van with Boots.
Boots?
I'll sweeten the deal for you.
You can do whatever
you want to this man.
- Wait, what?
- You can slap him,
you could karate chop him,
you can nunchuck him.
Knock him out again, kick him.
Okay, you can have a step
show on his old ass body.
I don't care. But come
play with us, man.
Come on, man.
I mean, what does that mean in kung fu?
Is that a yes?
Yeah, he's coming.
Yes. We got a giant on our team!
And I hope he can
play basketball.
Hey, man, what are
you doing, man?
You ain't supposed to
be behind the wheel.
I'm the getaway driver.
What you mean, you
the getaway driver?
Dude, we ain't rob a bank.
I got this, young
fella, I got this.
Oh, come on now, Lights,
you know you're not
supposed to be driving.
Come on, man. Not
even a block or two?
No, no, you can't drive.
Is that who I think it is?
Where the hell she come from?
- What's happening? What?
- Betty Lou is happening.
- Come on.
- Why are we scared?
- Who is Betty Lou?
- That's my wife.
I wasn't supposed
to leave the house.
Come on, Lights. You gotta
get out the car now.
- Drew, it's stuck.
- Wait, where is Big Fella?
Come on, we gotta move.
Shut up, I'm not talking to you.
Come on now, Betty Lou's coming.
- Who?
- Betty Lou's coming.
I'm gonna kill him.
Lights, don't worry
about the seat belt.
- I can drive?
- Gas it before she kill us!
Not a scratch, you hear me?
I got you, Drew.
- Buckle up.
- Punch it, fool!
Whoo-hoo!
You're going the wrong way!
You're going in reverse!
Lights, turn, turn!
Lights!
One voice, all right?
Ears can't take all
that hollering.
Incoming!
You got a old pickup to your left.
Just curl around it
like you're jumping
off to your spot.
Brace for impact!
Jesus, take the wheel.
- Pull over!
- No!
You don't know who you're
messing with, hobbit!
I'm not a hobbit, lady!
I'm a man!
Hit the freeway! She won't
drive on no highway!
Spin it to win it.
What?
Oh, y'all want me
to keep driving?
No!
I thought I did okay myself.
Here goes nothing.
Let's go, ladies. On the bus.
On the bus.
Hey, hey, Coach. Excuse me.
How you doin', man?
Dax Winslow, brother.
Are these girls just
wearing uniforms
just to be wearing them?
Or are they any good?
You're not from
around here, are you?
Two time, back-to-back
state champions.
I got $100 that say my guys
right here could destroy
these prom queens.
You got life insurance
policies on these guys, right?
Hopefully, you got their
parents' permission.
It would be impolite of
me not to take your bet.
- $100, man.
- Sold.
Look, guys, we need
to practice, okay?
What do you mean? Right now?
Look, this might be the
only opportunity we get.
What about Grandpa?
You know he can't
actually play, right?
Yeah, I figured the little
hobbit could take his spot.
Look here, Papa Smurf, okay?
Nobody asked you.
And, look, if we just gotta
play with four people,
then we'll do just four-on-four.
We got one day, one damn
day, until the Rucker.
We need to be prepared.
Meet me outside, guys.
Come on, Big Fella.
Let's go, Trojans.
Match up, now.
Pass the ball.
I'm open! Pass the ball!
Yeah, Preach.
Oh, yeah.
Make it rain!
That's a ladies' ball.
I'm open.
Come on.
Wait a minute.
Come on, guys, come on!
- Get down.
- Pass the ball.
- Hurry up!
- Move those old bodies!
Let me get some of that.
Wave me over. Match up.
Up top, up top.
Oh, this is bringing
back memories now!
- Got this.
- Goddamn!
Big Fella!
You mother...
Not exactly what you
were expecting, huh?
No, they are garbage.
Yeah, but they're smiling.
I mean, that's gotta count
for something, right?
Look at these guys. I mean,
Lights couldn't make a basket
if he had a braille trail to it.
Raindrop!
Big Fella and Uncle
Drew, they're talkin'.
- You're not open to me.
- Pass the ball, Kobe.
Come on, guys!
I got it.
Lights out, baby. Wait a minute.
You see? That's good basketball.
Barbeque chicken,
barbeque chicken.
Lobster in the house.
Big Fella! There you go!
There you go!
Better step out.
- Come on.
- Time out!
See the way they move
without the ball?
They're all connected as one.
Reminds me of us
back in the day.
Of us?
If they score one more
point, fellas, that's it.
Come on, Drew, you told
me these dudes can play.
This guy right here
can't even see.
Look, I'm standing
here doing this.
He don't even know I'm doing that.
Okay?
And this dude,
he's a karate man.
He's meditating right now.
Y'all gotta get it together.
Drew, it's on you now, man.
Stop passing the ball.
You are the lead singer,
the leader of this team.
You are Gladys Knight and
these dudes are the Pips.
It's just a scrimmage, youngblood.
That's all it is.
It's not just a scrimmage! Okay?
Look, I bet $100 on the game.
- What?
- What am I supposed to do?
Man, we don't have
no more gas left.
We're just runnin' on fumes.
What you want me to do?
Look, guys, they need to score
one more time. Just stop 'em.
You're really tall.
Just put your arms up,
they're little girls.
Come on, man!
Good job, guys. Stayin' alive, breathing.
Good effort.
Great teamwork, girls.
Great teamwork.
Good game, good game.
Good game, ladies.
Hey, Coach.
Pleasure doing
business with you.
Yeah. Me and the
fellas teamed up
to take care of that for you.
I just don't understand
why you ain't ask us
for the gas money?
It's not a big deal.
Just had to tell us.
And, remember,
Gladys Knight ain't
nothing without the Pips.
Listen, Drew, I really
appreciate you guys
having my back
back there, right?
But that doesn't take
away from the fact
that we got our butts kicked
by some teenage girls.
Matter of fact, maybe
we should look
- to get some more players.
- Forget that, youngblood.
My roster, my team.
Mind if we talk for a minute?
I was thinking about the way
we used to run pick and roll.
Might make sense if...
Fine.
Everything good
back there, Preach?
Just thinking about
my Betty Lou is all.
You'll be back in her
arms before you know it.
Yes! It may have took
us a while to get here,
but we are finally
here at the Rucker.
Some of the greatest
basketball players
you've ever seen have
played in this...
You mind giving us a
minute, youngblood?
Okay. Sure.
We're here, fellas.
Oh, man.
I played on damn near
every outdoor court
in the country over the years,
but battling between the lines,
with you fellas here,
always felt like home.
Feel you, Drew. I feel you.
I got each of you a
little something.
Now, I know you never liked
the way they looked,
but Doc put a lens in
there for a reason.
Take your time, now.
Now, go help him put it on.
Put it on.
Why didn't y'all say anything?
Man, y'all look so... So old.
I think he can see.
And, Preach. That face!
I can see! Lights out, baby!
Whoo-hoo!
Oh, yeah! Yeah, Drew.
Welcome home, Lights.
Welcome home.
I know you remember this one.
Gave it to me when we was nine.
You told me...
Told you it would
give you a strength
you didn't even
know that you had.
And it did. Now it's your turn.
Oh, come finish this, Preach.
Come finish it.
All right, Preacher!
Aw, yeah, baby.
Boots, you ain't think I
forgot about you, did you?
Left 'em back in the van in '68.
Figured they might still got
a little spring to 'em.
Yeah.
Just like you left 'em. Hmm?
I love you, too, bruh.
Easy now.
Let's see if they fit
before you start
going and getting all
emotional on me.
No, wait. Is he...
He can't get up. He...
Yeah. Yeah.
Oh, nice.
Look as good as the first
time you put 'em on.
Yeah.
Yeah, Bootsie!
That's it, Boots. That's it.
Kinda like breathing. Couldn't
forget how even if you tried.
I saved the best for last.
Brick City Two-on-Two
Tournament,
when we was 15 years old.
First tournament we
ever won together.
Yeah.
This ain't no apology.
Don't even try it.
Big Fella. Big Fella.
Hey, Jess. Come on, open up, it's me.
It's Dax.
Yeah, I got a team now.
I really think we got a chance.
Did it ever occur to
you to call first?
It did occur to
me to call first.
But I couldn't because you
cut my cell phone off.
That's because I broke up
with your pathetic ass.
But you know what?
My new boyfriend, he
took care of everything.
Wait, what you mean, you
got a new boyfriend?
We just broke up...
Hey, what's up?
What's that facial expression?
You look like someone
just took your girl.
Oh, that's right.
Oh, I think that's
what happened, though.
Yeah.
Sorry we couldn't
hear you knocking
- 'cause we was in the shower.
- Mmm-hmm.
We weren't gettin'
clean, were we?
No, we weren't.
- No, we were getting dirty.
- Dirty. You so dirty.
Y'all know I'm
standing here, right?
Can I just get my uniforms
and get out of here?
- Uniforms?
- Uniforms.
- How come?
- I got a team.
- You got a team?
- Yes.
- Aw, that's cute, bruh.
- Mmm-hmm.
- That's real cute.
- Here ya go.
Good luck. Hey, will
you cook me breakfast?
Mmm, I'll make you
an omelet, boo.
Oh, I'mma scramble your eggs.
Welcome, ladies and
gentlemen, boys and girls,
to the Rucker 50th
Tournament of Champions.
I am yours truly, Duke Tango.
Today we bring you
the best of the best
of the Rucker crowd
and $100,000.
That's right, $100,000,
and it's all here
in Harlem, US of A!
This is where it happens.
This will make you,
this will break you.
Here we go! Game one.
Hilltop Mavericks versus
Homecourt Advantage.
Let's do this! Let's do this!
Oh, yeah!
It's one of those days
when the crowd is a little thin.
Now, is it me or is
it empty in here?
Nah, Preach, it ain't you.
We used to ball out in front
of twice as many people.
Youngblood, I don't
know about this name.
Bruh, I'm straight
from Chocolate City.
Yeah, I think, guys, it's more
about where we are now...
Stop! Look, it's not
about the name.
We don't have a
fifth player, guys.
If we don't get nobody
else, we gotta forfeit.
We need Big Fella.
Where is he at?
He'll be here.
Yeah, but what if he's not?
I'm pretty sure those
basketball shoes.
Although, your
calf-to-shoe ratio
is not all that great.
Yeah, and his body's really bad.
It's not built for jumping.
Okay. Okay. Let me tell
y'all something...
I don't play basketball.
And, yes, my calves
don't match my body.
I done had these calves
since I was seven.
Went to a doctor, saw
somebody, and he was, like,
"Hey, man, we don't know
what we can do about it."
Yes! He is here.
The Black Messiah. Grandfather.
Okay.
- Don't. He is here...
- He's here.
Everybody get on the court.
Let's go.
What are you doing? Move!
Something you wanna say to me?
We're in the middle of a game!
Can we get some help out here?
I don't know what's going on
at the half court position,
but it ain't helping 'em.
Are they fighting?
I'm not running down
until you say it.
- Say what?
- You know what.
I'm not talking about her.
Hey, hey, hey, timeout.
Yo, yo, yo! Hey, hey.
Come here, bring it in.
What are you two doing?
I ain't run out on my old lady
just so we can come out
here and play like this.
I'm out.
Hey, nah, you're not
going nowhere, Drew.
You will stay right here.
And I don't know what
you two are doing.
You said you wanna
teach the kids
how to play the
game the right way.
But this is not the right way,
arguin' with your teammate.
Let's play some basketball!
We are a team.
Bring it in, guys. Come on.
Whatever y'all got going on,
work it out after the game.
Bring it in. Harlem
Money on three.
- One...
- Let's go get this money, man.
Come on.
Well, just play.
Back to live action,
here we go!
This is Boots with the ball.
Over to my man, Uncle. Uncle Drew, yes!
Uncle Drew!
This is The Mosquito
with the handle.
Oh, no, no, no! Steal
away for Uncle!
Look at the handle.
75 years old and still
can't admit it.
Selfish son of a bitch.
Uncle Drew doing it once again.
It's the third period, baby.
The Uncle Drew Show continues.
Harlem Money is running
away with this one.
Another basket and they will
be going to the next round.
How come you just can't
admit you messed up?
We hardly even knew her.
Matter of fact, I bet you can't
even remember her dang name.
You don't remember
her dang name?
I married her, punk.
Come on, baby. Come on.
You really wanna
make this right?
Stop running from the truth.
Can't believe you ended up
marrying her anyway.
Can't believe you slept with her
the night before the finals.
I loved her.
I don't know if you
knew this, but...
Yeah, I knew.
I always knew.
Spent five decades
pretending like I didn't.
But I saw the way
you looked at her
when she walked in the park.
So, why'd you do it, then?
I loved her, too.
Look, Big Fella, I'm sorry.
I've been sorry my
whole damn life.
You mean that?
I mean that with
everything I got.
If I can go back and
change it, I would.
Believe me.
I need you to feed me.
Excuse me?
You may not understand this,
but, uh, I can really
shoot the ball.
Let the Big Fella eat, huh?
Like The Last Supper, baby.
Oh, too slow, too slow.
Hey, that ain't no figment
of my imagination.
Somebody 'bout to
eat their words.
That's Drew there.
Hey, Drew, hey!
Look at that face! Go ahead,
scratch and smell him.
Scratch and smell him.
- You real.
- Yeah.
He real. He real man.
This ain't no hologram.
Been a minute, Angelo.
What's goin' on?
Oh, been a minute.
Good to see you, Drew.
Always good to see you.
What you gonna do with all
that money when you win?
- Come again?
- The purse. The purse, Drew.
The hundred stacks of
high society at stake.
You know, the duckets.
Wasn't ever no purse
back in the day.
No, it wasn't ever
nothin' like that.
But $100,000 of cash, baby.
I'd sign up, you know
what I'm saying?
You think I'm
stupid, youngblood?
Hundred grand is a
whole lot of money.
Look, man, I was gonna
talk to you about...
Yeah, when? When?
You just don't get it, do you, youngblood?
This game...
The love I got for it,
it's all sacred to me.
You told me that
you love the game.
You don't love the game.
You use it just like you use
everything else in your life.
You ain't nothing but a hustler.
Hey, man, who you
talking to, man?
Hey! Talkin' to you, man.
Watch your tone, youngblood.
You don't think I got
love for this game?
Don't nobody love this
game more than me.
Talkin' about Jordan, 63 against Boston.
I saw that.
Laettner's turnaround
against Kentucky.
Bird steals the ball to win
the Eastern Conference
Finals to beat the Pistons.
I saw all of that
and I loved it.
But guess what, the game
never loved me back.
So, then what happened then?
I missed a shot.
I shot it, it got blocked.
I was humiliated. Everybody
walked out on me.
Now, that's the first real
thing you've done said.
That's the real Dax.
Now, come on, let's
go play this game.
It's about the love,
youngblood, nothin' else.
- Yes!
- Get it, Grandpa!
This Big Fella. This
is the Big Fella.
Ooh!
Ah, shit, I'm loose.
Uncle looking at it. What
he gonna do with it?
- The Preacher!
- Oh, in the name of Jesus!
Finally gettin' my
legs back, y'all.
This is Uncle Drew to Lights.
- Money!
- All right, Lights!
The reason they call me Lights.
Yeah!
Don't bring your
little ass in here.
- And that's it?
- That's right.
You swipe right if you like
'em, left if you don't.
You couldn't even see the
day before yesterday.
Mmm-hmm. Exactly.
That's why I'm always
swipin' right.
It's more of a numbers game.
Looks a little different
these days, don't it?
She gonna get him pregnant if
she keep dancing like that.
If I wasn't so sore,
we'd get out there and
show 'em our old routine.
Excuse me, son, do we amuse you?
Yo, you're in the club, and
you're pushin' 80, bro.
And what's up with your
boy, Frederick Douglass?
Hey!
Heard he was doing great things.
Hold my beer.
Grandpa!
Don't hurt nobody, pop.
Ah, yeah! Gonna get real
grody up in this joint now!
Oh, my God!
Oh! Oh! Oh!
You know somethin', man? I did
not think your grandfather
would ever get up out
that wheelchair.
Me neither. I heard stories,
but I never knew he
could play like that.
So how much your
parents paying you
to watch your grandfather?
Why does anybody have
to be paying me?
Why can't I just enjoy
spending time with my family?
Well, I wouldn't know
anything about that.
'Cause I never had one. So...
What do you mean you
never really had one?
What do you call those guys?
I honestly had a lot
of fun tonight.
Me too.
Well, I guess it's time to go.
Yeah, we should go ahead
and get up out of...
He ain't gonna do it.
Hey.
- Hey.
- It's you!
No! Mmm-mmm.
- You open!
- Take a shot!
Sorry. I'mma go. I
need some water.
- Sure.
- 'Cause my throat is dry.
Yeah, I know how that is.
I'll take care of this.
Take a gap? Thank
you, appreciate that.
Yeah, yeah. Don't
worry about it.
Anybody give him some training
on how to talk to a lady?
Okay, look, man, I
don't wanna hear that.
Anything, okay? Not one
single freakin' word.
Maybe she should've
taken her heels off.
I'll tell ya, youngblood,
last time I checked,
you miss 100% of the
shots you don't take.
Yeah, let's get
out of here, man.
Let's give him a piggyback.
Big Fella, what are you doing?
We'll give him a
little piggyback.
That's right. Two down, two to go.
We almost there.
Yo, how's that geriatric
team of yours, bro?
You get 'em all individual
Life Alert bracelets?
Hey, man, are you
wearing my clothes?
- What?
- Yes, that's my shirt.
You got on my shirt, man.
That's right, I got
on your shirt.
Or maybe you got my shirt on.
- What? Wait, wait.
- That's my shirt.
- You got on my clothes.
- Stop it! You're crazy.
That's right. I'm crazy.
I'm being you.
The only way to
defeat one's enemy
is to become one's enemy.
- You're nuts!
- You're psycho!
I'll see you in the finals, Dax.
Psycho.
All day.
Yes! There you go, Big Fella!
That's what I'm talking
about, Big Fella!
Off shot! Handled it.
- Good rebound!
- All right.
Oh, shot, shot, shot.
Get that out of here!
- What do I do, what do I do?
- Just back up.
Oh, yeah. I remember this play.
Too late. Got 'em.
Yes! That's what I'm
talkin' about, Lights.
You are the man!
This is Boots. Boots
goin' down death valley!
Uh-huh! Baby!
Harlem Money is going
to the finals,
with only seconds
left in the ballgame!
- Still hungry, huh?
- Just a little dessert.
Hey, take the three,
Big Fella, why not?
This is to send 'em.
They're already there.
That's all right, Big Fella.
Big Fella.
Big Fella. Big Fella. Big Fella.
- Somebody get a doctor.
- Big Fella.
Come on!
Excuse me. Excuse me. Excuse me.
Let me in here.
The Big Fella is down.
Stay here, Big Fella.
Stay in it.
- Beginning CPR.
- Oh, Lord,
give him some room,
give him some room.
You're okay, boss.
Come on, Big Fella.
Doctor already said
he's been through
the worst of it.
So, what... What do we do now?
You don't stop playing
'cause you get old.
You get old 'cause
you stop playing.
Preacher!
Hi. And I'm so sorry
about the Big Fella.
Is he gonna be okay?
But I've been missing
you so much.
Come here, come here.
I missed you too, baby.
Now, look.
If you don't want me to go
ball, I don't have to ball.
Fool, please, after all this?
You're playing.
Matter of fact...
You saying what I
think you're saying?
I'm saying what you think
I'm saying, Preacher.
So we gonna ball?
So we gonna ball.
That's what I'm
talkin' about, boo.
Welcome! This is what we've
all been waiting for.
The new be versus the old.
The old be versus the new.
The good be versus the bad.
Are they gonna be a no-show
like they did in 1968?
But, no, they're not.
Here they come! They're here!
Here they come, baby!
Here they come! Aw, yeah!
We got a game on our hands!
Okay, Grandpa, you
gotta take your pills
before you start, okay?
Preacher, we gotta
take our pills.
Not the blue ones. Save
those for tonight.
It's all right.
What we gonna do?
- We gonna get this win.
- We gonna get this win, right?
Look, this one's for
Big Fella, okay?
So, Big Fella on three.
One, two, three.
Big Fella!
Here we go, C-Dawg!
Let's do this, baby.
You got this, Drew.
You the man, bruh.
You put this team
together, remember that.
Your roster, my team.
That's right, your team.
Last week, I took your team.
Yesterday, I took your girl.
Today, I'm gonna
take your heart.
Man, you've...
Okay.
- Stop it!
- Stop what?
- Folding your arms like me.
- Folding your arms like that.
Let's get this win, baby.
Good luck, youngblood.
Oh, luck ain't got nothing
to do with it, Old Dusty.
"Old Dusty"?
Pastor Wrinkles,
what's the word, man?
Young fella got jokes.
- Shoe ain't tied.
- What shoe? Huh?
- Lights!
- Championship time!
Oh, that's the oldest
trick in the book!
You gonna let him...
Oh, come on, now!
Over to Uncle. Jumper.
In and out.
That's okay, guys!
The bounce pass to Casper.
Casper, oh, my God!
Oh, yeah, I need you to see me.
Wipe your goggles, old fella.
I need you to see me.
- You gotta see me all night.
- Man, move. Fool, please.
- That's right, Casper!
- Come on, Drew!
This is Uncle.
Cross the mid-court line.
Betty...
Lights out! No good!
Oh, man!
That's right, old
people are overrated!
Over to Casper the
Friendly Ghost.
Nothin' but the
bottom of the net.
Wake up! Come on!
Up! Up! Up!
- You gotta love it!
- Yes!
Mario, comin' back down court,
kickin' it over to Beazy!
We makin' baskets!
That's right, we
makin' buckets, baby.
Uncle Drew the other way.
This is Betty!
Betty Lou jumper no good.
They fightin' for it, baby!
They fightin' for it!
Betty Lou wins it!
Get it, Betty Lou!
There you go, Betty Lou.
There you go!
You know that's really a man.
I got Drew.
Slow it down. Slow it down.
They tired, yo. They tired.
The fatigue's settin' in.
- Betty Lou. Switch it!
- Fatigue's settin' in.
You can hear their
knee caps grinding.
Uncle, Betty Lou.
Downtown!
You gonna let a
girl score on you?
This is Casper the
Friendly Ghost.
Oh, my God!
Oh, that's right.
That's right, baby.
- Oh!
- Oh...
Turnaround, once again.
The friendly one. What a goal!
Oh, baby!
Somebody get on
Casper, come on, man!
Casper!
Damn, man!
Homecourt Advantage
is running away
with the first half.
My TV ain't working.
Do I look like an electrician?
I know, right?
Oh, yeah, that was him. Brian.
Y'all got a TV?
Just judgin'. Me and her,
we're talkin' about Rachel.
Where you from?
What's your name?
I'm Kathy from Staten Island.
How you doin'?
Thank you. How you doin'?
Oh, wait. Come on.
You're my victim.
- I mean... I mean, my patient.-
That's my team right there. I
used to play on that team.
Okay, guys, bring it in.
Let's turn this game around.
So, on three, Big Fella.
One, two, three.
- Big Fella!
- Let's go, guys.
Harlem Buckets down by 16
at the start of the third.
Here we go!
Casper, the Friendly
Ghost from downtown!
Get in front of your man.
Boots with the ball.
Lookin' at it.
Boots makin' his move.
To Lights from downtown.
Not this time.
Reynolds Wrap to Casper.
Not today. Give me that.
Please, not in my house.
Come on, now. That's a foul!
- That's what I'm talkin' about.
- You know that's a foul.
Where I'm from, it's
no blood, no foul.
- Where you from?
- I just came from Hell,
whooping the Devil's ass,
that's where I'm from.
- Break it up.
- That's not godly.
They gangbangin' for Jesus.
Back to live action! Here we go!
Deflected! Goin' the other way!
Good block. Come on,
y'all, let's get it.
Uncle, look at him! Off the
backboard to Preacher!
Damn, man! Get the
ball, let's go!
My backboard, my house, sucker.
That's what I'm talkin' about!
Put it home, Preach!
That what I'm talking about!
This is Casper with it.
Kicks it over to Mario.
Jump shot. No good!
Yes! That's right,
y'all, we got this.
He kicks it over, right
side to Betty Lou!
Oh, my!
- Oh, my!
- Yeah!
Yes!
Uncle to the rescue!
Get on that old man!
Harlem Buckets are
trying to come back.
This is Casper with it.
Casper, looking at it.
Come on, now!
I got this.
B-B-B-B-B-B-Boots with it.
Booty through the
defender's legs.
Look at Boots.
Yes! Way to finish, man.
I can't believe it.
They're trying to
make a comeback.
Reynolds Wrap to Casper. For 30!
It's shut down time.
Now shoot, Betty Lou. Get 'em.
Over to Betty Lou! Good!
Get your head out your ass.
I knew I married you
for a reason, girl.
Game recognize game, big daddy.
Here we go. This is Uncle
Drew with the ball.
It's him and you, you and him.
What you gonna do?
Drew steps back.
Left-handed jumper...
What'd I tell you?
Harlem Buckets, baby.
Kicks it out over.
Oh, I got this. My board, my board.
Let's go.
Are you kidding me?
Here he go. Light the light.
- Bang!
- Lights out, baby.
That makes it a two point lead.
Here we go! The fast break!
There we go, there we go!
- Whoa.
- I got ya now!
That's what I'm talking
about, Lights!
- Get that outta here!
- That's a foul! Come on now!
- Lights?
- You see that defense?
You all right, Lights?
Get up, man. Get up.
Lights. Lights,
where does it hurt?
- Ankle.
- Okay, okay. Sit up.
Yo, that's bush league, Winslow.
You took out my player.
Man, what are you talking about?
Your boy, James Unworthy,
just knocked my boy out.
Cheatin'-ass cheaters. Y'all
need to cheat to cheat.
It's gonna be all right,
it's gonna be all right.
I'm getting too old for this.
What are we gonna do, bruh?
Lights is out. What we gonna do?
- What you mean?
- What you mean, "What I mean"?
We have no more players left.
It's your moment, ain't it?
No. I've already told
you a million times.
I'm not playing, okay?
Plus, I ain't played
in decades, bruh.
And they have?
Drew, it's different, okay?
They were actually
good when they played.
Listen to me, youngblood.
You think you're the only one
that made that mistake
that defined their life.
I've been on the
road my whole life.
I got no real friends.
I'm bouncin' city to city.
And you wanna know why?
Because I got too much
pride to say I'm sorry.
You know how that sounds?
Have too much pride
to say you're sorry
to the people that love you?
Don't you dare be like
that, youngblood.
You be better than that.
This is the moment.
You gonna run away from it,
or you gonna step
up and take it?
Choice is yours.
That's right, bruh.
Championships.
This is destiny now.
I'll play under one condition.
And what's that?
Let me guard the white boy.
Let's roll!
It's a minute and nine
second left, folks.
Excuse me. Timeout, timeout.
- Timeout, timeout!
- Who are you?
I'm the assistant coach.
I'm here to make sure that
he's tall enough to ride
the ride that my man
about to put him on.
What are you doing, man?
This should be a technical
foul or something.
I'mma kick you off this court
like I kicked you out my house.
- That's right.
- That's mean, okay?
Excuse me? I don't know
who you are or what
this is about,
but could you please take
it back to the stands
- so we can play some ball?
- Who are you?
If you keep talking,
you're gonna find out.
Oh, you about to
find out, honey.
I come from a long
line of choir members.
So, we gonna clap back!
- Yeah, that's right.
- I bet you do.
Just clap you up out of here.
Don't play with me.
- I will not!
- I love you, baby.
I love you, too.
We believe in you guys.
Be aggressive.
- All right.
- What am I doing now?
Brought your girl,
playin' mind games.
Ain't nobody scared of you, man.
Oh, ain't nobody scared of me?
- Let's do this, man.
- What's Dax doing in the game?
I got your back.
- Trail, Dax, trail.
- All right.
Yo help Uncle Drew.
No, move. Come on.
It's him and you, baby.
What you gonna do?
Let's go, baby. Let's ball, baby.
Vanilla Sky!
Oh, it's a four point lead now.
Come on, youngblood.
That's too easy.
Look, it won't happen
next time, okay?
Uncle gently across
the mid-court line,
with seconds left.
He's gotta foul whoever
may be guardin' him.
Uncle to Preacher.
It's the Preacher, man.
Oh, baby, hallelujah!
Praise the Lord, Preacher,
praise the Lord.
Here we go now.
Harlem Money in desperate
need of a turnover.
If not, Homecourt Advantage
can walk away and win it all.
Here we go.
What that white boy
doing with that ball?
Oh, he's doing his shaky-shake.
That's right.
Good steal, Dax, good steal.
Go on, Dax, shoot it!
Let it fly, Dax!
Shoot it, shoot it! Put it up.
- Come on, Dax! Shoot it!
- Take that shot, bro!
Shoot it!
Timeout.
Timeout? You gonna make me have
another heart attack, boy.
Hey, he fouled me on that.
You're saying he didn't foul me?
That was a reach, ref.
Let's go.
Okay, relax. Listen, I got this.
Drew, they can't guard you, man.
All we need you to do is just
penetrate to the bucket,
do what you've been doing,
the defense will
collapse on you.
Once they do that, you
kick it out to Betty Lou.
Betty Lou will take the three.
That's it.
Game over. Game plan. That's it.
What? Seriously, what's
wrong with that play?
You'll make it.
Excuse me?
Drew's right. They're
not even guarding you.
It's a reason for that, Lights.
Leave the past in
the past, move on.
You got this, Dax.
We don't need you to
be great all the time.
We need you to be
great this one time.
Can you do that?
We believe in you.
What if I miss?
What if you don't?
You got this.
Come on now.
Let's go. Let's bring it in.
We in this together.
You got this. Buckets on three.
One, two, three.
Buckets!
Preach, Preach, Preach.
In case something happens, we
got no more timeouts, okay?
You sure?
Yeah, I'm sure. We
used our last one.
I could have swore
we had one more.
This is it. This is for
the money in the bank.
This is for all the marbles.
Come on, come on, Dax.
Buckets, down by two,
a three can win.
Eight seconds left
in the ball game.
This is Uncle with it.
Uncle, looking at it.
Uncle over to Hobbit.
Yes, we won the Rucker, baby!
We won the Rucker.
That's what I'm
talkin' about, baby!
We did this, man! We did that!
You the man!
Mookie! Hey, Mookie!
Good game, man.
Good game, bro.
I see what you're doing now.
Playing mind games with me.
Okay. I'll see you next year, bruh.
The cycle continues.
Fellas, we did that, y'all.
Pick him up!
Pick me up? Hey! No, no, no.
He's way too heavy, boy.
His head too big.
Head weigh about a
hundred pounds.
I'll be back, y'all.
Hey.
Oh. This is nice.
- I'll be back.
- Okay.
There ya go. That's what
I'm talking about, young fella.
The hero, Dax.
Man, I'm damn proud of you.
You took that last shot.
You miss a hundred percent
of the shots you don't take.
Game ball goes to you.
Your team. Your roster.
Nah. My family.
Big Fella, man, I'm really
happy that you're okay, man.
And if anything...
We were all really...
Okay, look, I paid the bill.
Thanks.
I had to pay the bill.
You know why?
That's what you do for family.
Shh! You still talking?
Hey, check it out,
we're on SportsCenter.
Everyone was clowning
him, including us.
Well, you're number one tonight
in the right top ten
for this right here.
Dax Winslow, all three of these,
and the Harlem Buckets
win the Rucker 50.
I'm still baffled by a
lot of this guy's story.
I don't understand a lot,
frankly, but I know this much.
He went from a
punchline to a hero,
getting carried off
on his teammates'
shoulders in Rucker.
Way to go, Dax.
Yo, yo, yo,
here's the coach of the year.
Dax is here, baby.
I be the Rucker champ.
Just leave a message, you know,
when I give you the chance.
Hey, Dax, it's, uh, me, Jess.
When you get a chance,
give me a call back.
Hey, Dax, it's me again.
Your phone must be dead,
'cause it went right
to voicemail.
Do you remember when I
made that investment
in them shoes? Do
you remember that?
You remember that? Do
Do you remember that?
I wanted to let you
know that I went ahead
and kicked Mook to the curb.
Uh, I noticed the phone went
straight to voicemail again.
Do you remember that? Hey.
Dax, do you remember that?
I am affiliated with
several gangsters.
I will find out where you at.
We gonna come over
to your house.
I let you stay in my house
rent-free for all that time.
I hate you, Dax.
But I love you so much.
I don't know why you're
doing me like this.
- You know what?
- You, Dax!
Gotta make sure I get
the behind the scene,
behind the scene.
Yeah.
I appreciate you guys
following me to makeup.
But now, you gots to go.
Wow!
Kyrie's under here somewhere.
Uh-huh. No.
Hey, girl. Lights
just called me.
Preacher, you put your Bible
in the club and can't find it?
Hold up. Wait a minute. Hold on.
I can't play in that tourney
and let that little white
boy block my shot again.
Give me a pudding even though
it's gonna give me diarrhea.
Hey, I don't mean
to grab your face.
I'm sorry.
Hold up, hold up. Run
it back, run it back.
Don't you wanna go with a coach
who straight up looks like Urkel
got put in a trash compactor?
Isn't that what you want?
Wait a minute. Run that back.
Just run it back.
Don't you wanna be coached
by a dude who looks like an M&M?
Double or nothin' this time.
Double or nothin',
double or nothin'.
Hey, man, you don't
blow no whistle in my gym.
Okay, that's... Okay... Stop!
Or little hobbit here
could take his spot.
Who you callin' a
hobbit, Uncle Ben?
Uncle Ben?
You heard what I said.
Get me some rice.
No, no, no...
Youngblood, I can't take this
rappity-hippity-hop nonsense.
You say "hippity-hoppity."
That's something
rabbits would make.
If rabbits made music,
it would be called
hippity-hoppity.
You know how old this van is?
Older than you.
I assume it is, brother.
Lots gone down in here.
Somethin' went down here,
stained that seat.
Feel good about that.
Got a microwave in here,
you got carpet everywhere.
Ain't no tellin' what old women
you'd have back there.
Probably had your
momma back there.
- You ever say...
- Ooh!
I'm an orphan, for
your information.
So I don't know who my momma is.
This is what we call a ditty now.
Ooh.
My lady... That ditty just crazy.
Mmm!
I got it. This is
the real version.
We not goin' be disrespecting
a classic like that.
That came out before you was...
- You have to drive.
- Oh, I forgot.
Get out of here. Go!
Courses. I've come a
long way since Kazaam.
That is sick!
I found him in a grocery store
putting cans on the top shelves.
That's all he's good for.
I'm sorry.
You are my Beyonce, okay?
Not Dantay, not White
Dantay, not Jeff,
and not the dude who look like
he sang with New Addition.
I'm so sorry.
Rapid fire. I gotta
go rapid fire.
Here we go. Watch
this right here.
Ow! Ow!
What is this, man?
That look like a dead inch worm.
Who you trying to be?
Morgan Freeman?
You played a heck of
a game today, sir.
Appreciate you
saying that, Coach.
You ever think about
re-taking those SATs?
You have four years left
of eligibility, right?
I'm more of a Blue Devil
man myself, Coach.
Come on, Dax!
Oh, too late, Drew. Too late.
Your old-ass legs broke
up on you, Drew.